sandiego.org 2019-08-10

# Privacy Policy & Terms of Use - The Official Travel Resource for the San Diego Region

Thank you for visiting SanDiego.org, the official travel resource for the San Diego region. This site is operated by San Diego Convention and Tourist Bureau dba San Diego Tourism Authority (SDTA), a private non-profit, mutual benefit corporation composed of approximately 1,000 member organizations, businesses, local governments, and individuals seeking a better community through the visitor industry.  For the purposes of any data collected, SDTA is the data controller and may be contacted via email or written letter at the following addresses:

OR

San Diego Tourism Authority  
Attn: Marketing Services Department  
750 B Street, Suite 1500  
San Diego, CA 92101

We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of the users of our website and the personal data they may provide to us. This privacy policy and terms of use statement describes the type of information that we gather through our website and digital platforms, how we use and disclose that information, and the steps we take to protect user information. By visiting the San Diego Tourism Authority website or digital platforms, or by purchasing hotel reservations or tickets using the third party services connected to the SDTA website or digital platforms, you accept the privacy practices and terms of use described in this statement and/or the privacy practices of those third party services, as applicable.

This privacy policy and terms of use statement was last updated in May 2018.

**INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE**

When you visit the SanDiego.org website, social media channels and other SDTA digital platforms, we collect information about you, your visit and your engagement in a number of ways. 

Our web server automatically recognizes site visitor traffic through non-personally identifying information that the browser you used makes available. This information includes things like your domain, the type of device used and Internet browser, geographic location, the date and time of site visit, duration of visit, pages access, and the referring page (the webpage that contained the link to our site that you clicked on to get there). We aggregate this information with other site visitors and use this information to measure performance, analyze user traffic patterns, and improve the overall website experience. You may also find links to third party services through the SanDiego.org website and such third party services may collect additional information from you.

At times, we may request that you provide us with personal data.  We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where you have provided consent for us to use your personal data.
  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

We may provide your personal data to our service providers such as our payment processors if you should choose to make a purchase through the SanDiego.org website and provide such personal data to us.  We will keep your personal data only as long as necessary to provide you with our services and for legitimate business purposes such as maintaining the performance of our services. Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time. You may always request that we delete your personal data, and we will honor such request, as further outlined below.

**COOKIES**

We also use "cookies" on the website and in digital advertising (a small piece of data stored on the user's computer by the user's web browser while the user is browsing) in order to provide a better user experience and customized advertisements, content and information. The use of cookies is a standard practice among Internet websites and most Internet web browsers. Through your computer settings, and through some Internet browsers, you may customize your user experience to reject or delete cookies. Please note, some features on this site may not function properly without cookies. You can find out more about cookies by visiting [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

**INTEREST BASED ADVERTISING**

Interest based advertising is the collection of data from different sources and across different platforms in order to predict an individual’s preferences or interest and to deliver to that individual, or his/her computer, smart phone or tablet, advertising based on his/her assumed preference or interest inferred from the collection of data pertaining to that individual or others who may have a similar profile or similar interests.

We work with a variety of third parties to attempt to understand the profiles of the individuals who are most likely to be interested in visiting San Diego so that we can serve our advertisements to them on websites, social media channels and other partner website and entities. These third parties include: (a) advertising networks, which collect information about a person’s interests when that person views or interacts with one of their advertisements; (2) attribution partners, which measure the effectiveness of certain advertisements; and (3) business partners, which collect information when a person views or interacts with one of their advertisements.

In collaboration with these third parties, we collect information about our customers, prospects and other individuals over time and across different platforms when they use these platforms or interact with them. Individuals may submit information directly on our website, social channels or on platforms run by third parties, or by interacting with us, our advertisements, or emails they receive from us or from third parties. We may use special tools that are commonly used for this purpose, such as cookies, beacons, pixels, tags, mobile advertising IDs, flash cookies, and similar technologies. We may have access to databases of information collected by our business partners.

The information we or third party collect enables us to learn what engagements with San Diego content the person made, what ads or content the person sees, on which ads or links the person clicks, and other actions that the person takes on our website, social properties, or in response to our emails, or when visiting or using third parties’ platforms.

Users may opt out of receiving interest-based advertising by advertising networks that may be delivered to them on our platform and other websites by visiting the following website: [optout.aboutads.info](http://optout.aboutads.info/)  This site feature will opt a visitor out of many – but not all - of the interest-based advertising activities in which we or third parties engage.

**DO NOT TRACK POLICY**

California law requires that operators of websites and online services disclose how they respond to a Do Not Track signal. Some browsers have incorporated “Do Not Track” features. Most of these features, when turned on, send a signal or preference to the website or online service that a user visits, indicating that the user does not wish to be tracked. Because there is not yet a common understanding of how to interpret Do Not Track signals, we do not currently respond to Do Not Track signals. We continue to follow the industry and will implement this service once a common understanding of how to treat Do Not Track signals is defined.

**SERVICE PROVIDERS**

We work with third party service providers who provide website, application development, hosting, maintenance, payment processing, and other services for us. These third parties may have access to, or process non-personal and personal data as part of providing those services for us. We limit the information provided to these service providers to that which is reasonably necessary for them to perform their functions, and our contracts with them require them to maintain the confidentiality of such information.

**SOCIAL MEDIA**

If you create an account using Facebook Connect, we have access to any information you have made public on your profile, and may collect and store that information. Similarly, if you have made public posts from your other social media accounts that include our specialized hashtags, we may collect and use that information to learn more about you.

**SURVEYS, SWEEPSTAKES, ONLINE FORMS & EMAIL**

The San Diego Tourism Authority does not collect personally identifying information such as name, address, telephone number, etc., unless you provide the information voluntarily. We may ask for personal information so that we can tailor the interactive features of our website to your specific interests and to provide information you have requested such as Visitor Planning Guides and Email Newsletters. We may also capture personal information from you if you complete an online survey.

The San Diego Tourism Authority makes commercially reasonable efforts to comply with all state and federal laws, including CAN-SPAM. You can opt-out of email communications from us at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions in any email you receive from us, or by sending an e-mail to sdinfo@sandiego.org that contains the email address you wish us to unsubscribe from our lists.

In the event that the San Diego Tourism Authority conducts an online promotion, contest, or sweepstakes, information we collect will be used consistent with the terms and conditions outlined in the rules and regulations. If the promotion involves the collection of your mobile phone number, a check-box will be provided to opt-in to receiving automated text messages during the promotion and once the promotion has ended, and you need only text “stop” in reply to any message you receive in order to opt-out. You are not required to provide your mobile number for any discounts or coupons. Coupons or other special offers we provide you via text message may also be acquired through an email address by sending an email to [sdinfo@sandiego.org](mailto:sdinfo@sandiego.org) with “coupon” in the subject line. The San Diego Tourism Authority makes commercially reasonable efforts to comply with the Telephone Consumer Privacy Act, and will not contact you unless you have given prior express consent to receive messages from us.

Any personal information you provide will not be sold to outside companies or organizations. However, we may share your information with key business partners, marketing partners and affiliates, who may perform functions on our behalf, who may have products and services we believe are of interest to you. We have contractual relationships with partners and affiliates that require them to safeguard your information and comply with US law, which includes allowing you to easily opt-out of any future communications. 

If you would like us to delete all of your personal information (except for information that we keep for record-keeping purposes) and/or remove your name and address from promotional lists (including any personal information gathered by our service providers) and place your name on our “do not contact” list, contact us at [sdinfo@sandiego.org](mailto:sdinfo@sandiego.org) and provide us with details of what you require.  We will make commercially reasonable efforts to delete your information from our active files. Please note that requests to update your personal information may take up to 10 business days.

We may release personal information if we believe in good faith that: the law or legal process requires it; we have received a valid administrative request from a law enforcement agency; or such release is necessary to protect our rights, property, or safety, or that of our respective staff, affiliates, business partners, customers, or others.

**MINORS AND CHILDREN’S PRIVACY**

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. Our website and digital properties are not directed to children under the age of 18, and we do not knowingly collect personal data from children under the age of 18 without obtaining parental consent. If we learn that personal data has been collected from persons under 18 years of age and without verifiable parental consent, then we will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under 18 years of age has shared their personal information with the San Diego Tourism Authority then you may alert us at sdinfo@sandiego.org and request that we delete your child’s personal data from our systems.

**BUSINESS TO BUSINESS & RFP FORMS**

Some of the online services available through the San Diego Tourism Authority’s digital platforms require you to provide personal information or information about your company. In order to access these services, such as Request for Proposal Forms, Travel Agency Sales Tools and Specialist Quiz, and other B2B applications, you will be asked to complete detailed forms such as name, email address, business address, IATA number, and details about your service needs.

If you would like us to delete all of your personal and company information (except for information that we keep for record-keeping purposes) and/or remove your name and address from promotional lists, place your name on our “do not contact” list, contact us at [sdinfo@sandiego.org](mailto:sdinfo@sandiego.org) and provide us with details of what you require.  We will make commercially reasonable efforts to delete your information from our active files. Please note that requests to update your personal information may take up to 10 business days.

**HOTEL & TICKET BOOKINGS**

The San Diego Tourism Authority contacts aRES Travel, Inc., a private-label booking engine, to provide online reservations and ticketing transactions through links on our website to hotels.sandiedgo.org. We may also contract with other providers such as Booking.com, etc. to provide online reservations on other digital platforms. When you make a reservation or purchase tickets through one of these booking providers, they will provide the hotel, attraction or other partner with a limited amount of information provided voluntarily by you (including credit card information) for the express purpose of placing and confirming your reservation or ticket purchase with the designated travel provider. Your data is transmitted via an encrypted message (SSL) and will not be sold or otherwise released to any third party. For more information about aRES Travel, Inc. privacy policy visit [www.arestravelinc.com/privacy/](http://www.arestravelinc.com/privacy/)

**INFORMATION ACCURACY**

While we provide links to other websites, once you leave the SanDiego.org website, you will be going to sites that are beyond our control and you are subject to the privacy policy of that site. The San Diego Tourism Authority is neither responsible for nor guarantees the content or accuracy of any member pages or other sites linked to or referenced from this website. Although the San Diego Tourism Authority tries our best to keep our website and other digital properties up-to-date, information such as website addresses, event and attraction details, ticket prices, hotel information, room rates, special promotions, driving distances, current weather information, etc. may change and therefore may not be accurate. If you are concerned, please call the business directly to confirm the accuracy of the information. In addition, member businesses and other sites that we link to may have their own privacy policies, or no privacy policies at all. The San Diego Tourism Authority is not responsible for the privacy practices employed by other sites and those other sites have not agreed to our privacy policy. The San Diego Tourism Authority has no control over or responsibility for any unaffiliated third-party sites or the content contained in them, and we provide these links solely for the convenience of our website visitors.

**WEBSITE LINKING POLICY**

The San Diego Tourism Authority reserves the right to accept or reject any and all hot links to our website or digital properties from external websites. You may request a link by contacting [webmaster@sandiego.org](mailto:webmaster@sandiego.org). The requirements listed below must be met to post a link from your website to SanDiego.org:

  1. Link must be labeled “San Diego Tourism Authority Official Website” which takes users to SanDiego.org.
  2. The business/event must be directly involved in tourism related activities within San Diego County.
  3. The link must point to a website or internal web page with specific business objectives directly related to information provided on the SanDiego.org website - i.e. it must add value.
  4. The website must be user friendly and easily readable.
  5. The website/page must be separate from non-tourism related content, advertising or non-tourism third-party links.
  6. The website must be fully operational. Websites that, in whole or in part, are “Under Construction” will not be approved.
  7. All information on the website must be current and up-to-date, including any events calendar.
  8. The website may not be used for sales of non-tourism related services or products, including real estate of any type.
  9. The entire website must be void of any political commentary, campaign information, hate speech, or content that advocates a political position or candidate, either directly or through a third party.
  10. The entire website must be void of pornography, or include the sale or representation or anything illegal. 
  11. Inclusion of a link to your URL does not imply, nor may it be used to indicate, endorsement or recommendation by the San Diego Tourism Authority.
  12. If your link is denied, you will be notified by email as to the reason for that denial.  Denied links may be resubmitted once the discrepancies are corrected.

**SITE SECURITY AND DATA TRANSFER**

We take reasonable and appropriate security measures to protect unauthorized access, alteration or destruction of data located on and collected by our website and other digital properties. We exercise reasonable care to protect your non-public personal information. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. While we strive to protect your non-public personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us or receive from us while it is in transit. Once we receive your personal information, we maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect it.

We ensure your personal data is protected by requiring all our group companies to follow the same rules when processing your personal data. 

Many of our external third parties are based outside the European Economic Area (EEA) so if you are inside the EEA and you provide personal data to us our third parties through SanDiego.org, the processing of the personal data you provide will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

  * We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. 
  * Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US.

**POLICY CHANGES**

We reserve the right, at our sole discretion, to change, modify, add or remove any portion of this privacy policy and terms of use in whole or in part, at any time. By using this website and the SDTA digital properties you agree to be bound by any such revisions and should therefore periodically visit the page to determine the then current terms of use to which you are bound.

**ADDITIONAL GDPR NOTICES**

The San Diego Tourism Authority makes commercially reasonable efforts to comply with all international laws, including the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR). If you wish to access, rectify, erase, opt-out or otherwise amend any personal data we hold about you, you may contact us at [sdinfo@sandiego.org](mailto:sdinfo@sandiego.org) with the subject line “GDPR compliance”. Please note that while any changes you make will be reflected in active user databases within a reasonable period of time, we may retain all information you submit for backups, archiving, prevention of fraud and abuse, analytics, satisfaction of legal obligations, or where we otherwise reasonably believe that we have a legitimate reason to do so. At any time, you may object to the processing of your personal data, on legitimate grounds, except if otherwise permitted by applicable law. If you believe your right to privacy granted by applicable data protection laws has been infringed upon, you may lodge a complaint with our CFO Rick Meza at [rmeza@sandiego.org](mailto:rmeza@sandiego.org). You also have a right to lodge a complaint with data protection supervisory authorities, the identity of which may depend on your location. This provision does not apply to personal data that is part of our B2B client database. In this case, the management of our client data is subject to the terms of service for our business division and request for access, correction or deletion should be made to the account manager responsible for maintaining your client relationship.

**OPT-OUT FROM COMMUNICATIONS**

If you receive commercial emails from us, you may unsubscribe at any time by following the instructions contained within the email or by sending a written letter to us at the following address:

San Diego Tourism Authority  
Attn: Marketing Services Department  
750 B Street, Suite 1500  
San Diego, CA 92101
